<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[JλO]]></title><description><![CDATA[Mah blog]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 06:01:25 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Elastic and Zdog]]></title><description><![CDATA[(drag the logo （　ﾟДﾟ） )]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com//elastic-and-zdog/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com//elastic-and-zdog/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 04:40:35 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h5&gt;(drag the logo （　ﾟДﾟ） )&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;height: 400px; width: 400px; margin: 0 auto;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe style=&quot;height: 100%; width: 100%;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;../zdog-elastic-logo.html&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[On The Chariot]]></title><description><![CDATA[*Tana-ta-tana-ta-tana-ta-tana-ta**Tana-ta-tana-ta-tana-ta-tana-ta*This is the last chance you get… Open wide!— The ChariotFor many people…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com//the-chariot/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com//the-chariot/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 13:50:43 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Tana-ta-tana-ta-tana-ta-tana-ta*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Tana-ta-tana-ta-tana-ta-tana-ta*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the last chance you get… Open wide!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;cite&gt;The Chariot&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people who are familiar with &lt;em&gt;The Chariot&lt;/em&gt; this refrain should stand
out as an iconic overture on the track &lt;em&gt;Back to Back&lt;/em&gt; from the album &lt;em&gt;The
Fiancée&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OpyhEKlQqZw&quot;&gt;music video here&lt;/a&gt;.
The moments which follow are a visceral, jarring assault on your senses.
Well, your sense of hearing to be more precise. Most to whom I’ve played
this, or other &lt;em&gt;Chariot&lt;/em&gt; tracks, have generally responded with a strong
aversion, disgust or incredulity that music like this exists. More
interestingly, this response is present regardless of whether the person in
question listens to broader categories of alternative music (e.g., heavy metal) or not.
I find these responses totally understandable — perhaps even a
desired outcome. It’s just a cacophony. And an especially obnoxious cacophony
at that&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of your initial response, I’d like to invite you to consider
my case; that &lt;em&gt;The Chariot&lt;/em&gt; presents unique art, painstakingly and
lovingly crafted with an incisive message for modernity. &lt;em&gt;The Chariot&lt;/em&gt;
unpacks an interpretation of our modern milieu that is as shrewed as the
music is unhinged — which is worth taking stock of. I submit to you
this post as my brief post-mortem review on &lt;em&gt;The Chariot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without delving to deeply into the origins and interlinked nature of music
genres it is worth noting that &lt;em&gt;The Chariot&lt;/em&gt;’s roots are in punk rock.
Telltale signs being present in song brevity, aggressiveness, minimalistic use
of chords (at times) and charged lyrical content. Math Rock (syncopated,
irregular rhythm sections) combined with punk roots create a hardcore sound
also present in bands like &lt;em&gt;Norma Jean&lt;/em&gt; and, more along the Math Rock
tangent, bands like &lt;em&gt;The Dillinger Escape Plan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first heard &lt;em&gt;The Chariot&lt;/em&gt;’s music when I was in eleventh grade, back in 2009.
Their album &lt;em&gt;Wars and Rumours of Wars&lt;/em&gt; had recently been released and a
friend of mine played the track “Daggers” to me. At the time the accompanying
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K05weZYExPU&quot;&gt;music video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;
demonstrated that this band is not a typical group — they had something to
say. The insignificant cartoon army-men being dropped into the midst of war
with the sun happily(?) shining down on them depicts the way in which human life
is undervalued by proud detached leaders. This particular song is clearly a protest against the powers that be with the repeated
phrase: “War, it’s only skin deep”. Like many bands in the genre they sounded
really angry, but about what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Chariot&lt;/em&gt;’s first album &lt;em&gt;Everything Is Alive, Everything Is Breathing,
Nothing Is Dead, and Nothing Is Bleeding&lt;/em&gt; is even a challenge to the
convention of album titles (at the time). By the time they released
&lt;em&gt;One Wing&lt;/em&gt; the music and presentation were honed to a razor sharp edge. With
tracks “In” seasoned with
aphorisms: “We’re all capable of love, we’re all capable of cancer” and
“Love.“‘s (one of all my all time favorites) lyrics “You fell in love [with the world], you fell
asleep”. These lines reveal a theme: a reclamation of what was lost and
supremacy of individual decision-making while affirming the accompanying responsibility that come
with our decision-making powers — all delivered in a tongue-and-cheek manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The band’s primary driver and creative force Josh Scogin went through several
line up changes. He nurtured and maintained the band’s vision. Scogin is a
self-proclaimed adherent to the Christian faith and his lyrics contain many
references to Paul and Christ. However, in keeping with the nature of art,
Christianity is not a prerequisite for resonating with lyrics like “We hold
our breath as we pass everyone sleeping…” which occur in a meadow-like
dream section of the track “Tongues”. This section speaks out as a call for
action in the presence of overwhelming inaction, presumably apathy. As an
overall body of art &lt;em&gt;The Chariot&lt;/em&gt; is a Nietzschean grip around the shoulders
and call for an honest evaluation of one’s life and surroundings with
motivation to consequent action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One gets the sense that this of music seeks to undo the confidence with which
humankind establishes and venerates it’s ideologies as superior and correct -
to me this is particularly true of the West’s cultural pattern. &lt;em&gt;The Chariot&lt;/em&gt;’s
music attempts to warn against the dangers of oversimplification and occasionally
depicts humanity grasping at straws, endlessly seeking for unifying theories
but only discovering paradox leading to deepening anxieties, unless we can
somehow awaken to our place in the world. &lt;em&gt;The Chariot&lt;/em&gt;’s music says the
following is solid ground: between the tireless categorization and
compartmentalization that has served advancements in how we, as humans,
organize ourselves and technology and the acknowledgement that we actually
have no idea what we are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have seen exceptions to this rule, individuals with whom The Chariot resonate off the bat. Emphasis here on &lt;em&gt;exception&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The music video for “Daggers” may contain the first &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K05weZYExPU&amp;#x26;start=75&quot;&gt;instance of dabbing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>